Stealing supplies.
Of course.
Thank Brigade Commander Cui
for bringing us this news.
Go back and tell him,
tell him it's just like last time.
He gets the credit, and I get the goods.
What goods do you want?
Do you even need to ask?
The weapons from the Japs, of course.
As for the grain,
however the Japs stole it,
we'll return it the exact same way.
Right.
Just like last time,
he's being greedy and wants everything.
He asks me to team up against the Japs,
yet he negotiates terms with me.
What is he thinking?
Commander,
what should we do next?
Remember this.
We can't be short of food or weapons.
If those bandits try to rob us,
show them no mercy.
Yes.
Brothers.
There's an opportunity now
to teach the Japs a lesson
and from their hands,
seize weapons.
Are we doing it?
Yes, fight the Japs!
Avenge our brothers!
Alright.
Brother, give the order.
We'll all listen to you.
Alright.
We got news.
The Japanese are short on supplies.
Lately, they've been sending small squads
one by one
to villages around the county to loot grain.
If we set up an ambush in advance
and attack them,
we can snatch
weapons from them.
We can also return the grain to the people.
Weren't we just worrying about having no weapons?
The Japanese are delivering them right to us.
Master.
The premise of an ambush
is to figure out the exact route of the enemy.
We need to find out which road the Japs will take
and which village they will pass through.
We need to know everything.
Master Liu,
you really are a veteran who has led troops.
I have it all figured out.
Master Liu,
you lead a team of swordsmen
to the villages around the county town.
As soon as you see Japs entering the village,
send us a message.
Okay.
I will be Uncle Liu's assistant.
You are careful, so you can look after him.
Then we will follow the rules of our swordsmen.
Once we spot the Japs,
we will send a smoke signal.
Okay.
Send a smoke signal.
Master Liu,
Master Liu and I will lead a team
to the vicinity of the county town.
Once we see the signal,
we will lay an ambush at the location.
Okay.
Did everyone hear that?
Get ready, everyone.
Yes, sir.
Go, go, go.
Report.
Come in.
Brigade Commander,
Cai Baozi sent a swordsman to see you.
Brigade Commander Cui,
Boss Cai asked me to pass a message.
He said to act when you see the smoke signal.
If you're late, the prey will be taken away.
Alright.
Go back and tell your boss,
I will be there as promised. I won't leave until we meet.
Brigade Commander Cui, I'll take my leave.
Notify the troops to get ready.
Let's go up high and see the view.
Yes.
Uncle Liu.
We've already been through three villages.
Are the Japs not coming?
No one can figure them out.
Don't worry yet, let's look ahead.
Miss, Master Liu.
How is it?
Saw the Japs entering Zhang Village ahead.
Okay, hurry back.
Keep an eye on them.
Yes.
Catch up quickly, go.
Go.
Stop.
Good view here.
Right here.
Unload all the grass.
Hurry up, make it quick.
Hurry.
Everyone listen up.
When we enter the village later,
as soon as you see the Japs,
follow my orders.
Don't linger, finish the fight quickly.
Protect the civilians.
Yes, sir.
Baozi,
come here.
Smoke is rising ahead.
Judging by the direction,
it's from Mageta Village.
Mr. Liu,
you lead a team from the west,
and I'll lead one from the east.
We'll meet up outside Mageta Village
in the woods later.
Okay.
Follow me.
Brothers, follow me.
Let's go.
Go. This way.
Go. Go.
They showed up.
Commander, is it the Japanese
or Cai Baozi?
This road leads to Mageta Village.
We absolutely can't make a losing deal today.
Get the brothers ready.
Yes, sir.
Attention! Right face!
Move out!
Fellow villagers,
the Imperial Army said
as long as you hand over enough rations,
they won't make things difficult for you.
Please tell them.
It's a year of famine.
Our village
had a hard time gathering this much grain.
We even brought out next year's seeds.
We really have nothing left.
Tell them
they must hand over enough,
or none of them will leave alive.
Yes, sir.
Chief, the officer said
if you don't hand over enough grain,
none of you will live.
We really have nothing left.
Nothing left.
What should we do?
Exactly.
What is this?
Why hasn't he arrived yet?
Master Liu, Miss.
How is it?
The Japanese devils are forcing the commoners to hand over food.
If they don't hand over enough, none of them will survive.
How many of them are there?
Twenty or thirty.
And they have machine guns.
I'm not waiting anymore. Follow me.
No.
Uncle Liu, we can't be impulsive.
Baozi said
we are here to ambush,
not to attack.
We must follow his arrangement.
I'm dying of anxiety.
He's here.
Brother, Ying'er.
Master Liu, Baozi.
The devils have already entered the village.
The machine guns are already set up.
Why is there still no sign
of Cui Wenkui?
Brother, we can't wait any longer.
If we keep waiting,
who knows how many more civilians these Japs will harm.
Everyone, come here first.
Come down quickly.
I've decided.
We're not waiting anymore.
Some of us will blend in with the civilians,
while the rest ambush them from around.
In our first wave of attack,
we take down their machine guns first
and seize them for ourselves.
This time fighting the Japs,
it's not about winning or losing.
We just want their weapons.
Of course,
the more Japs we kill, the better.
That way, they won't dare enter the village so casually next time
to harm the civilians.
We hit them and run.
This is a pit courtyard.
It extends in all directions.
Everyone hide in the tunnels in time.
As long as you have a chance to escape,
run back here to regroup immediately.
Did everyone understand?
Understood.
Sixth Master, Ying.
You guys guard this place
and cover everyone coming back.
Look, brother,
don't underestimate me.
I'll definitely show you my skills today.
Let us go together.
There is strength in numbers.
Yeah.
Alright.
But you must obey orders during the operation.
Okay.
Everyone, get ready.
Move out.
Go.
Fellow villagers.
Don't fight them head-on.
How about everyone goes back and prepares some more grain?
Village Head.
if we hand over this little grain,
my whole family will starve to death.
If we had grain,
my mother wouldn't have starved to death.
Since they're going to kill us anyway,
just let them kill us.
Yeah, don't.
Don't.
Stop wasting your breath on them.
Get ready.
Fellow villagers, get down!
Mr. Liu.
Stop chasing!
Don't prolong the fight.
Quit while we're ahead.
Catch.
Retreat!
Let's go.
Keep up.
Fire!
Hit them hard!
They're trying to surround us.
Captain, they clearly have too many men.
I know a small path in the back
that goes around to the county town.
Go back and report to the Colonel.
Go.
Say it again.
Initial estimates suggest
they have a division of troops.
They are attempting to surround us.
If I hadn't fought to break out,
I would have already died for the Emperor.
Bastard!
Get out!
Yes, yes.
Colonel.
I heard we were ambushed.
We suffered heavy losses.
So I asked you here to discuss it.
We need to teach them a lesson.
Colonel.
Now you know how cunning
these Chinese are, don't you?
You have clearly occupied this place,
but you have to face the fact
that you will coexist with them.
They are in the dark, and you are in the light.
You will never catch them,
but they hit you with perfect accuracy.
Tahara, you really understand them.
I've been dealing with them for a long time.
Then who did it this time?
If I'm not mistaken,
it should be led by the commander of the Independent Brigade,
Cui Wenkui.
He was the one supervising the construction of that airport.
Later, Zhang Gongyan came.
That guy embezzled a lot of money from the airport,
so the airport was delayed.
Now the airport is occupied by the Empire,
and those bandits have been scattered by us.
I will definitely report to my superiors
and recommend you for promotion to Lieutenant Colonel.
Thank you, Colonel.
Did you add the sentries?
We set up three layers of sentries.
As soon as they see the Japanese coming out,
they will send up a smoke signal.
Not bad.
You learn fast.
The methods of these swordsmen
are sometimes quite effective.
But we really stirred up a hornet's nest this time.
The Japs will definitely retaliate.
Be prepared.
Cai Baozi got off easy this time.
He just hit and ran.
Now the Japs are coming after us.
You shouldn't say that.
Who's talking about me?
Brigadier Cui, look what I've brought you.
That's it?
You're generous.
Sit down.
Brigadier Cui.
We both get what we need.
Neither of us loses out.
What?
Don't be too greedy.
You want both fame and fortune?
Now the whole world is talking about you, Cui Wenkui,
giving the Japanese army a head-on blow.
You see,
the newspapers in the rear
will definitely boast about you.
All the credit
goes to you, Cui Wenkui.
What else do you have to lose?
Besides,
especially after Zhang Gongyan left,
you won a great victory.
You really got a bargain and still act innocent.
Let me see your mouth.
How come you're getting sharper and sharper?
Just tell me,
coming to my place,
what other bargain do you want me to get?
It's no longer safe
for you to be stationed here.
If the Japanese army spots you,
they'll attack you sooner or later.
You'd better relocate as soon as possible.
Fangmin, Cai Zhongkui
So you do know how to worry about my safety.
Jokes aside,
I'm talking serious business with you now.
Tell me, what intelligence do you have?
Based on my understanding of the Japanese,
they will eliminate any resistance
one by one.
Right now, the swordsmen's strongholds
have mostly been wiped out.
Your Nationalist force is the only one left in Shanzhou.
Think about it.
Even if you don't attack them,
they will attack you.
What's your trick?
You know me well.
Exactly.
I think,
rather than sitting here waiting to die,
we should take the initiative
to disrupt the Japanese army's plans.
We need to lead them by the nose.
We can't always be passive
and follow their lead.
Be specific.
In Mageta Village,
you made the enemies suffer in silence.
It was us.
Same thing.
The enemies will definitely retaliate wildly.
Instead of staying here to fight a positional war with them,
we might as well take the initiative to attack.
Attack their weak points,
and hit them where it hurts.
Yongbaodunian sanshisan guomin caozhong.
Why are you so talkative today?
Just tell me the target.
Straightforward.
Qinglong Stronghold.
Qinglong Stronghold?
Why are you so sure
that I, Cui Wenkui, will agree
to attack Qinglong Stronghold with you?
We've gathered intelligence
that Masao Tahara is in Qinglong Stronghold,
hoarding a lot of food and ammunition.
Moreover, this location
controls three major routes.
If the National Army counterattacks Shanzhou one day,
the threat of Qinglong Stronghold
must be eliminated.
You just said it yourself.
Masao Tahara is personally stationed in Qinglong Stronghold,
and they have ammunition.
What are our chances of winning?
We can lure Masao Tahara out first.
As for Qinglong Stronghold,
we have our own ways.
It won't be hard to break in.
Sir.
Cui Wenkui usually seems quite smart.
But at the critical moment,
you are the one who shows true leadership.
Mr. Liu, you flatter me.
For this matter,
I will still need your great help.
Me?
No problem.
Let's hurry up.
We still have a lot to discuss when we get back.
Okay.
I have conveyed all the superiors' instructions to you.
You know what to do now, right?
Secretary Peng Tao's instructions on uniting
the remaining swordsmen of Sandaoyuan are very important.
I feel much more confident now.
Attacking Qinglong Stronghold this time
can firstly
give confidence
to the swordsmen around us,
and secondly,
rally more swordsmen to our cause.
Come, have some water.
You've had a hard journey.
How are your wounds?
Miss, I'm fine now.
Thanks to Wenpei along the way.
She helped take out the bullet
and took good care of me.
Don't say that.
If it weren't for me, you wouldn't have been injured.
Alright. The trip was not in vain.
You came back just in time.
Perfect.
Let's study my plan carefully again
and see if there are any loopholes.
Look here.
This is the armory.
This is the gate of Qinglong Stronghold.
How can we
reach the armory in the shortest time?
I received intelligence
that the Japanese army's defense at the airport
has been very weak lately.
It's a good time to take it back.
So I've decided
to attack the airport soon
and take back what we lost.
Are you confident?
Yes.
Good.
High morale.
We can only win battles with high morale.
Brigade Commander, beware of eavesdroppers.
What are you muttering about? Speak up.
The Japanese secret police are everywhere.
What are you afraid of?
I'm going to fight back.
Right turn,
double time, march!
Zhang Gongyan ran away.
That is good news for us.
I don't think it's good news.
Zhang Gongyan is nothing to fear.
He is the easiest type of Chinese to deal with.
He saw us take the airport,
feared he'd be attacked next,
so he slipped away quickly.
Cui Wenkui is extremely difficult to deal with.
He is an opponent of the Great Japanese Empire,
a true diehard.
Colonel,
the spy you sent out has returned.
Sir.
They train every day, and their morale is high.
It is said they are going to attack the airport.
Do you know
the consequences of providing false intelligence to the Imperial Army?
If you dare to provide false intelligence,
you will be beheaded.
It is absolutely true. There is no mistake.
He says it is absolutely true. There is definitely no mistake.
You may go.
Yes.
Go.
Tahara, do you think this information is reliable?
I think it's highly credible.
It matches the information gathered
by the people I sent out.
Attacking the airport?
They really don't know their own strength.
The Imperial Army
is invincible.
The Kuomintang's main forces
were all beaten back by us.
This small unit still wants to attack the airport.
How ridiculous.
Colonel.
I have an idea.
Please go ahead.
Since they don't know their own strength,
there's no need for us to show mercy.
Aren't they planning to seize the airport?
Then we won't even give them a chance to set off.
We'll head straight for their base,
uproot them,
and catch them like rats in a trap.
Brilliant. Absolutely brilliant.
If they go to attack the airport,
we'll raid their nest.
We'll split into two groups
and head straight for Lijiayao Village.
Attention!
Brigadier, everything is arranged.
Once the sun comes up,
have everyone else hide.
Yes, sir.
Tonight,
we will make a forced march overnight.
No lights and no noise.
Violators will be dealt with by military law.
Understood?
Understood.
Prepare to move out.
Target:
Qinglong Stronghold.
Brigadier, didn't you say we were attacking the airport?
Has everyone remembered
what I said?
Got it. Got it.
Good.
I want to emphasize one more point.
Follow orders in all actions.
Okay, okay.
Sir,
we should go.
Okay, let's go.
Let's go.
I leave things at home to you.
Please look after Xiaoni.
Don't worry.
Wait for our return.
Stay alert, everyone.
We are almost at Qinglong Mountain.
Mr. Liu.
What's the situation?
The scouts ahead report
that a troop is approaching.
I guess it's Cui Wenkui and his men.
They set off at night.
They should arrive around this time.
Ying'er, let's go greet them.
Sixth Master, Master Liu.
Please wait here for a moment.
Okay.
Commander Cui.
We have been waiting for you.
I also marched through the night.
I didn't delay anything, did I?
Right on time.
Have your troops
take a short rest in this forest.
Let's discuss our attack strategy.
Follow me, everyone.
Halt.
What's going on? Something's wrong.
Something doesn't seem right.
A military camp shouldn't be
this quiet at this hour.
In a moment, you'll lead the Nationalist army brothers
and attack through the main gate of the stronghold.
We will attack the stronghold through the secret passage
and seize the armory directly.
You're getting more and more calculating.
You want me to lead my brothers
and attack through the main gate.
And you go through the secret passage?
For use in the 33rd year of the Republic of China.
The main gate has the most guards.
Do you think I'm stupid?
Cui Wenkui.
Am I, Cai Baozi, that kind of person?
The Japanese soldiers in the stronghold right now
have all been taken out by Masao Tahara.
They've all gone to your camp.
Have you forgotten?
The Empty Fort Strategy is set up for them.
I don't know if the information is reliable or not.
Don't worry, it's absolutely reliable.
Uncle Banjin saw Masao Tahara early this morning
leading his troops down the mountain.
The remaining swordsmen in the stronghold
won't put up much of a fight either.
For use in the 33rd year of the Republic of China.
With the two of us attacking from both the front and the shadows,
how can we not take down Qinglong Stronghold?
For use in the 33rd year of the Republic of China.
It's a deal then.
The spoils of war,
half for each.
Great.
Empty.
Bastards!
Colonel.
We've been tricked.
Everyone has evacuated.
Evacuated?
When?
Probably last night.
Last night?
Are they planning a sneak attack on my airfield?
Judging by the distance and time,
it shouldn't be the airfield,
but my Qinglong Stronghold.
Come with me.
Keep up, those in the back!
Okay!
Keep up.
Got it!
Move faster and stay close!
Platoon Leader Zhu.
Yes, sir.
Find a few men to guard the gate.
The rest of you, follow me.
Hurry up.
Move.
Everyone, get ready.
Boss.
Someone is attacking the stronghold.
They've already reached the gate.
Did you see who they are?
It's the National Army.
The National Army?
What should we do, Boss?
Don't panic. Let's go take a look.
Put your guns down!
Drop your guns!
Listen up, swordsmen.
Your Miss Shangguan Ying is back!
Brothers.
I know you were forced.
Put down your weapons.
We won't make things difficult for you.
Right.
We only kill Japanese devils.
If you refuse to be Chinese,
and are willing to be Japanese traitors,
then don't blame us for showing no mercy.
Drop your guns.
Put down your guns.
Is everyone all right?
Where is your boss?
Speak.
Master Liu, I saw him run that way.
Ying, wait here.
If that kid Tianyuan knew
Issued in the 33rd year of the Republic of China.
we tricked him,
what expression would he have right now?
Who cares about his expression.
As long as we got Qinglongzhai back.
We didn't come back this time
to retake this place.
Before Tianyuan Zhengxiong gets back,
we need to find an opportunity to destroy this place.
This is my father's life's work.
Yinger.
Qinglongzhai is no longer what it used to be.
Its existence
directly threatens the nearby
anti-Japanese armed forces of the villages.
I agree with Baozi.
All right, let's not talk about this.
We need to go to the armory first.
Master Liu, take us there.
Cui Wenkui, have your men guard the gates
in case Tianyuan Zhengxiong comes back.
You don't need to tell me. It's already arranged.
First Squad Leader!
Here!
Get the men to seal all the gates.
Yes, sir.
Follow me.
Let's go.
Keep up.
The Jap's armory is right here.
It really is an inconspicuous place.
This is a deserted courtyard.
There was a fire here back then,
and the whole family burned to death.
The people in the stronghold thought it was unlucky,
so they sealed this place off.
Tianyuan sure knows how to pick a spot.
In this godforsaken place,
who could find it?
Quite a lot of stock.
Enough for us to use for a while.
Yeah.
What do you mean enough for you to use for a while?
Didn't we agree on half each?
Don't worry.
A promise is a promise.
You'll get your share.
Report.
What is it?
Brigade Commander, the Japanese are attacking.
They came in large numbers. We've suffered heavy casualties.
What about the weapons?
Take as much as we can.
Blow up whatever we can't take.
Okay.
Brothers, hurry!
Only take the good stuff.
Hurry up!
Hurry!
Careful!
Brothers, hurry!
Baozi!
Go!
The armory!
They blew up my armory!
Bastards!
Don't move. Behave.
Come on!
Platoon Leader Zhu, what's the situation?
Brigade Commander, casualties are too high.
We can't keep fighting like this.
Hold them off!
Yes, sir!
Master Liu!
Go, follow me to the secret passage.
Retreat!
Hurry!
Hurry up!
Keep up.
Hurry!
Take this.
Hurry, keep up!
This way.
Where?
Hurry!
Here!
Keep up.
Keep up, hurry!
Hurry!
Keep up!
Son-in-law, you take Ying'er and go first.
Master Liu, you lead everyone to retreat first.
I'll cover you.
I know the secret passage better than you.
If you don't go, Ying'er won't go either.
Hurry up and go!
Master Liu!
Baozi, tell Uncle Banjin to leave right now.
Hurry up and go!
Little Japs!
Yes, sir!
Brother,
I'm coming to join you.
Bastard!
Bandage the wounds cleanly.
The bones are fine. That's good.
Uncle Banjin and Uncle Liu haven't caught up yet.
Could they be in danger?
Yes.
Master Liu is familiar with the secret passage.
Even if he encounters the Japs head-on,
he should be able to get away safely.
What I'm worried about now is Master Liu.
Baozi.
It's too close to the stronghold here.
We need to move.
Master Liu and Master Liu haven't come back yet.
We want to wait for them a bit longer.
Don't they know the way?
How about this.
You take the Nationalist brothers and withdraw first.
Moving together makes too big of a target.
That works too.
But you absolutely cannot stay too long.
The Japanese are very likely to counterattack.
That would be bad for you.
Wenkui, if you have nowhere to go,
go to our underground courtyard.
There is plenty of space there.
Thanks.
If I have nowhere to go,
I will definitely bother you.
You are welcome anytime.
Take care.
Stay safe.
Platoon Leader Zhu.
Here.
Assemble the troops.
Yes.
He Xiaobian,
you must give me an explanation today.
Major.
You took all the men away.
There were only a few people left in the stronghold.
It wasn't that we didn't want to fight,
we were short of hands.
Even if we wanted to fight back, we couldn't beat them.
So you're saying it's my fault?
I wouldn't dare say that.
But I also find it strange.
Why didn't they attack earlier or later,
but exactly when you left with your troops,
they came to attack the stronghold?
Isn't it obvious that it was all arranged?
Bring the captured man up here.
He Xiaobian.
You ungrateful son of a bitch.
The boss trusted you so much,
but little did he know he was raising a wolf.
Not only did you bite the boss to death,
you also handed Qinglong Stronghold to the Japanese.
You son of a bitch.
Are you even human?
Don't you want to fight back?
I'll give you a chance.
Kill him
and prove it to me.
Come on.
I'm not afraid.
He Xiaobian,
you are just a Japanese lapdog.
Come on. Kill me.
Major.
You can't kill this man.
Didn't you ask me to recruit swordsmen?
This man is the sixth boss
of the swordsmen in Sandaoyuan.
Many people take orders from him.
If we kill him,
I'm afraid it will provoke public outrage.
Keeping him alive can be useful to us.
Are you confident
in persuading him to listen to us?
I know this man.
He is all brawn and no brains.
I have my own ways.